<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amy H. Herring | Bora Jin</title>
    <link>/author/amy-h.-herring/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/amy-h.-herring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Amy H. Herring</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:55:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Amy H. Herring</title>
      <link>/author/amy-h.-herring/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Predictions on Physically Constrained Domains: Applications to Arctic Sea Salinity Data</title>
      <link>/project/boragp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:55:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/boragp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motivated by applications in point-referenced geostatistics that have measurements collected and meaningful only within a constrained domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop the Barrier Overlap-Removal Acyclic directed graph GP (BORA-GP), a scalable GP method that incorporates the constrained domain via sparsity-inducing DAGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable characterization of dependence in constrained domains by removing an edge in a DAG if a linear path between two points overlaps physical barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyze sea surface salinity in the Arctic Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Matrix Completion for Hypothesis Testing</title>
      <link>/project/bmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:55:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/bmc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapt Bayesian heteroscedastic nonparametric regression to a multiple hypothesis testing framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impose a generalized latent factor model to form a non-exchangeable prior for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a matrix completion method for a latent matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tackle sparsity of the ToxCast data using hierarchical framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable prediction for non-tested chemical’s activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broaden the definition of activity including heteroscedasticity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To appear in &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Statistical Science: Series C&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of PFAS on North Carolina Thyroid Cancer Clusters</title>
      <link>/project/nc-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 12:55:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/nc-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify thyroid cancer clusters in North Carolina.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reveal spatial, causal, and socioeconomic relationships between the cancer clusters and PFAS in drinking water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
